Guide to the Nate Millard snowboarding video collection 1990s-2000s
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Nate Millard snowboarding video collection
1990s-2000s
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 801-581-8864 http://www.lib.utah.edu/collections/multimedia-archives/
A0230
Millard, Nate
19 VHS videocassettes
The Nate Millard snowboarding video collection (1990s-2000s) consists of snowboarding, skateboarding and surfing videos filmed in Utah and around the world. Videos range from small local productions to larger commercial enterprises. Nate Millard is a freelance photographer currently employed by Brighton Ski Resort's Brigtown Chronicles.
Biographical Note
Born and raised in Connecticut, Nate Millard moved to Utah in 1997 to pursue snowboarding, and school. While snowboarding on a regular basis, he would meet his now wife, Bree, who was also riding for various snowboard companies and competing nationally. He picked up the art of photography from Bree, who was going to school for a Bachelor of Arts in Fine Arts Photography. Nate began working as a freelance photographer in the early part of the century, and has been published in a number of publications locally, and worldwide, as well as producing, co-filming, and editing two local videos, "Crew Cuts", and "No Sugar Added". Bree and Nate continue to ride and shoot snowboarding together for Brighton Resort, as Brigtown Chronicles.
Biography written by Josh Scheuerman.
The Nate Millard snowboarding video collection (1990s-2000s) consists of snowboarding, skateboarding and surfing videos filmed in Utah and around the world. Videos range from small local productions to larger commercial enterprises. With the exception of one damaged videocassette all materials have been digitized and are available to view on DVD.
Materials are arranged alphabetically.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
Donated by Nate Millard in 2012.
Utah; Snowboarders; Snowboarding.; Skateboarders; Skateboarding.; Surfing.; Sports and Recreation; Moving Images; Moving images
- 411 VM Skateboarding, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 1)
  Production Company: 411 Video Magazine. Boarders: Jason Adams, Colt Cannon, Rodney Jones, Danny Montoya, Ed Selego, Jeremy Wray, Kenny Anderson, Daniel Shimizu, Justin Strubing, Tony Silva, Chet Childress, Jason Adams, Kristian Svitak, Tony Trujillo, Chad Tim Tim, Fabrizio Santos, Jamie Thomas. Locations: Puerto Rico, Oregon, Brazil.
- Big Youth Happening, 2000; VHS videocassette (Cassette 2)
  Production Company: Volcom.
- Brainstorm, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 3)
  Production Company: Kingpin Productions. Boarders: Chad Otterstrom, David Carrier Porcheron, Joel Mahaffey, Jason McAllister, Ali Goulet, Gigi Ruf, Andrew Crawford, J2, Seth Huot, Josh Dirksen, Mikey Leblanc, Lukas Huffman, Chris Coulter, Blusie Rosenthal.
- Common Thread, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 4)
  Production Company: Elevation. Boarders: Tom Burt, Nate Holland, Victoria Jealouse, Dan Mccoy, Carlo Mondavi, Noah Salasnek, Kelly Clark, Tara Dakides, Jake Devine, Andy Hetzel, Karleen Jeffries.
- Crew Cuts, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 5)
  Production Company: D.F.L. Productions. Boarders: Brandon Christensen, Josh Isaac, Dave Van, Nate Millard, Grayson Millard, Brad Hatcher, Mike Handley. Location: Utah.
- Empress, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 6)
  Production Company: Misty Productions. Boarders: Megan Abubo, Lisa Andersen, Rochelle Ballard, Layne Beachley, Serena Brooke, Jamie Burge, Cara-Beth Burnside, Barrett Christy, Tara Dakidas, Wendy Fisher, Alison Gannett, Sarah Gerhardt, Victoria Jealouse, Karleen Jeffries, Keala Kennelly, Jen O'Brien, Jamie Simon, Nicola Thost, Julie Zell.
- Hardly Angels, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 7)
  Production Company: XX Productions. Boarders: Doriane Vidal, Pauline Richon, Janna Meyen, Tara Dakides, Karleen Jeffery, Natasza Zurek, Jamie Burge, Tina Basich, Shannon Dunn-Downing, Kelly Clark, Roberta Rodgers, Nicola Thost.
- Kick Ass Blasters, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 8)
  Production Company: B.C. Surf & Sport. Boarders: Jared Winkler, Steve Duke, Todd Haag, Chris Taylor, Josh Issac, Clay Wells, Dustin Anderson, Chris Coulter, Rhys Haag.
- Luminous Llama, 2000; VHS videocassette (Cassette 9)
  Production Company: Volcom Stone. Boarders: Bjorn Leines, Terje Haakonsen, Wille Yli Luoma, Joel Mahaffey, Daniel Franck, Billy Anderson, Jeff Anderson, Erik Leines, Michi Albin, Janna Meyen, Gigi Ruf, Romain, de Marchi, Shaun White, Ben Ashburner, Micah McGinnity, Mikey Leblanc, J.J. Thomas. Locations: Utah, Colorado, Washington, Oregon, California, Japan, Norway, Chile.
- Meet Your Maker, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 10)
  Production Company: XYZ Clothing Company. Boarders: Danny Way, Tas Pappas, Ben Pappas, Chet Thomas, Justin Bokma, Pat Channita, Pat Duffy, Pat Moss, Bil Weiss, Peter Hewitt, Chris Strother, James Crow, Ryan Hughes.
- Mervin: The Mockumentary, 1999; VHS videocassette (Cassette 11)
  Production Company: XYZ Clothing Company. Boarders: Jamie Lynn, Temple Cummins, Dave Lee, Barrett Christy, Joey McGuire, Javas Lehn, Wes Makepeace, Danny Kass, Jakob Wilhelmson, Kai Arne Lein, Matt Cummins. Locations: Mt. Baker, Whistler, Jackson Hole, Teton Pass, Crystal Mt, North Cascade Heli, Telluride Japan, Mt. Hood, Valle Nevado and Chillan Chile, Brohn Ridge B.C., Weigle's.
- No Sugar Added, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 12)
  Production Company: D.F.L. Productions. Location: Utah.
- Our Turn: An All Girls Film, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 13)
  Production Company: XX Productions. Boarders: Serena Brooke, Jamie Burge, Cara Beth Burnside, Layne Beachley, Barret Christy, Tara Dakides, Shannon Dunn, Victoria Jealouse, Prue Jeffries, Karleen Jeffrey, Keala Kennelly, Melanie Redman, Trudy Todd, Doriane Vidal, Julie Zell, Natasza Zurek. Locations: Alaska, California, Canada, Europe, Hawaii, Mexico, Tahiti.
- Oversteez, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 14)
  Boarders: Mike Kansa, Mitch Allen, Matt Carter, Knut Carter, Lance Hacker, Scott Johnston, Treu Hahnenberger, JP Tomich, Justin Hebbel, Mike Hacker, Tyler Laitinen, Chris Roslinac, Jason Hindman, Nate Millard, Tom Miller, Key, Reid Laitinen, Travis Robison, Takashi Nishida, Gaku, Frank Wells, Spencer Tamblyn, Mats Hanson, Nima Jalali, Derek Rue.
- Skateboarding Inside Out, Circa 1995; VHS videocassette (Cassette 15)
  Production Company: Gullwing. Boarders: Kahuna, Char Pipes, Extra, Lake Factory, Kettners 14, Marsha's Pool, Baldy Line, Fallbrook Open, El Cortez, Tiajuana, Pleasures of Pain, Cedar Crest, Baldy Pipe, Mini Ramp, Ocean City, Parking Lot Wall, Late Open, Fallbrook, Andy's Ramp, Vegas Van, Houston, Vegas Banks, Coronado, Black Bowl, Downtown San Diego, Roxy Rails, No Way Walls, Malcolm X, Texas, Kona, Orange Juice Pipes, Lands Downe, Curb Skating, Arizona.
- Stand & Deliver, 2001; VHS videocassette (Cassette 16)
  Production Company: Mack Dawg Productions. Boarders: Gaetan Chanut, Kevin Jones, J.F. Pelchat, Mark Frank Montoya, Tara Dakides, Chris Brown, Keir Dillon, Mitch Nelson, Dionne Delesalle, Allister Schultz, Kale Stevens, Shaun White, Trevor Andrew, Brandon Bybee, Jason Brown, Daniel Franck, Matt Hammer, Jason Murphy, Terje Haakonsen, Jason Borgstede, Dave Downing, Willie Yli-Luoma, Nicolas Droz.
- Technical Difficulties, 2000; VHS videocassette (Cassette 17)
  Production Company: Mack Dawg Productions. Boarders: Peter Line, JP Walker, Devun Walsh, Chad Otterstrom, Chris Brown, Joni Malmi, Bjorn Leines, Mikey LeBlanc, Dave Downing, JF Pelchat, Todd Richards, Kevin Jones, Josh Dirksen, Wille Luoma, Jason Borgstede, Brian Thien, Chris Dufficy, Tara Dakides, Blaise Rosenthal, Allister Schultz, Jeremy Jones.
- Weapons of Mass Destruction, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 18)
  Production Company: CKC & AK-49. Boarders: Mitch Allen, Aaron Biittner, Dan Brissie, Matt Carter, Knut Carter, Ryne Dopple, Erik Gabrielson, Mats Hanson, Drew Hoefer, Pat Howell, Mike Kansa, Luke Kretschmar, Heath Lillie, John Makens, Rory Marenco, Andre Spinelli. Locations: Solitude Mountain Resort, Utah Backcountry, Montana Backcountry, Alaska Backcountry, Salt Lake City.
- The End, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 19)
  This video is damaged and unavailable for viewing. Production Company: Birdhouse Skateboard. Boarders: McCrank, Reynold, Berra, Santos, Kirchart, Lasek, Klein, Hawk.